<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhigyan Kishor</title>
    <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abhigyan Kishor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 21:41:41 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics 4 and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/google-analytics-4-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 21:41:41 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/google-analytics-4-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>So you want to add GA4 to your Hugo website? Here is a step-by-step guide to adding Google Analytics to your Hugo website.
  Setup a Google Analytics account   Head over here and make an account (or sign in if you already have one).
Create a property (accessed through admin), add a stream, and point it to your site URL.
Once done, head over to admin &amp;gt; property &amp;gt; Data Streams and go to your newly created stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 456</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-456/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 16:43:52 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-456/</guid>
      <description>132 Pattern Head on over here to try the problem for yourself.
This one was so annoying :&amp;rsquo;(. I ended up following this tutorial for ironing out the final cases.
  Algorithm The goal is to maintain a descending monotonic stack to keep track of the minimum value present before each element in the stack. The ideal case is for the ith index to be as small as possible, the jth index to be as large as possible, and the kth index to be somewhere in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Custom Domain</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/how-to-custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 20:43:37 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/how-to-custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>So you want a custom domain name? Here is a step-by-step guide to how to get one (for free) from freenom. I use github pages to host my hugo website so the tutorial will focus on the relevant steps.
  Check availability of a domain name   In the search bar, type out the site name that you want, say example.com. It should give you a few alternatives such as shown in the picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 1209</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-1209/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 12:49:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-1209/</guid>
      <description>Remove All Adjacent Duplicates in String II Head on over here to try to the problem for yourself.
The problem requires a stack based solution.
Algorithm The goal is the find the shortest string possible by removing k duplicated adjacent characters. A simple problem case is illustrated:
k = 2 s = &amp;#34;abbac&amp;#34; the result must be c. Iteration 1: remove bb =&amp;gt; &amp;#34;aac&amp;#34; Iteration 2: remove aa =&amp;gt; &amp;#34;c&amp;#34; The hint points out that instead of maintaining the character count outside the stack, just pass in an object that stores the counter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 225</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-225/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 15:39:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-225/</guid>
      <description>Implementing Stacks Using Queues Head on over here to try the problem for yourself.
The solution talks about using 2 queues, which frankly I don&amp;rsquo;t understand :&amp;rsquo;). I used a single queue to implement this problem.
Algorithm The goal is to implement a stack using the basic queue features provided such as push(), peek() and pop(). The easiest way to implement this is by inserting elements in reverse order. Then the queue will pop the elements like a stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 1769</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-1769/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:27:17 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-1769/</guid>
      <description>Max Number of K-sum Pairs Head on over here to try the problem for yourself.
This is a varaition of the famous two-sum problem that we have all struggled with :)
Algorithm &amp;amp; Code The slower O(n) The goal is the count unique pairs of integers that sum up to given k. For this, we create a hashmap that stores unique values of the integers. Then we go over the keySet() and update the count according to the following rules:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 581</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-581/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 17:10:04 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-581/</guid>
      <description>Shortest Unsorted Continuous Subarray Head on over here to try the problem for yourself.
I solved this problem using a two-pointer method.
Algorithm The goal is to find the points where the array becomes unsorted. We use two loops, one to find the end of the unsorted sub-array and another to find the start of the unsorted sub-array. start = end = -1 as a way to check if they were updated or not during the loops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 905</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-905/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:36:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-905/</guid>
      <description>Sort Array by Parity Head on over here to try the problem for yourself.
I attempted a two-pointer approach to try and solve it.
Algorithm The goal is to try to return the parity array in one pass. For this reason, I create a new array result[] and two pointers, evenPtr, pointing to the start of result[] and oddPtr, pointing to the end of result[]. Now I loop over the initial array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leetcode 844</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-844/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 17:55:32 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/05/leetcode-844/</guid>
      <description>Backspace String Compare Head on over here to try the problem for yourself.
There are a few ways discussed in the solutions. I will try to explain the two-pointer method.
Algorithm The goal is to try to build the resultant string in one pass. For this reason, we will iterate over the string backwards. If we encounter #, we simply skip the first valid character that follows. Ofcourse, the caveats are considering more backspaces (#) than actual words, in which case we simply get an empty string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloo Gobi</title>
      <link>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/04/aloo-gobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 19:46:10 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.abhigyankishor.ga/posts/2022/04/aloo-gobi/</guid>
      <description>How to cook - Aloo Gobi Sabzi (dry) Ingredients:    Item Quantity Processing     Cauliflower one head cut small floretd &amp;amp; rinse   Potato 1-2 medium sized cut into cubes and rinse   Garlic 1 large/ 2 small clove crushed   Cumin 1 tsp    Hing 1/4 tsp    Turmeric (haldi) 1/2 tsp    Chilli powder 1/4 tsp    Coriander powder 1 tsp    Oil (sarson) 1-2 serving spoon     Procedure:   Put the pan/kadai on the fire.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
